#### Contact

+88 01682324580 (Mobile) yeasminnilo@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/nilufaryeasmin-a5412454 (LinkedIn) www.maheenlabel.com/ (Company)

## Top Skills

TypeScript Node.js Git

## Languages

English (Professional Working)
Bengali (Native or Bilingual)

#### Certifications

Angular (Basic) Certificate Baseline: Data, ML, Al

# Nilufar Yeasmin

Sr. Software Engineer at Continental Technologies Bd Ltd Narayanganj District, Dhaka, Bangladesh

## Summary

**Experienced in Angular Framework** 

In-depth Knowledge about Javascript, TypeScript.

Good knowledge in cross-platform and cross-device compatible Working knowledge in Git

Experience in User Interface and user experience design.

Good understanding in responsive websites development.

Create consistent user experiences and visual designs on products ranging from websites, to mobile

Highly skilled in Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, PHP, Zend Framework Sass etc.

Experience of Javascript, jQuery.

Proficient with design tools: Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator.

Experience in designing web applications for various platforms(iPhone/iPad/Android/PC).

Strong knowledge on web standard, usability best practice and UI trends.

# Experience

Continental Technologies Bd Ltd Senior Software Engineer October 2021 - Present (3 years 3 months) Narayanganj District, Dhaka, Bangladesh

Directing software development projects.

Producing clean code.

Leading a team of engineers.

Developing information systems by studying operations.

Designing, developing, and installing software solutions.

Supporting and developing software team.

Designing and implementing new systems and features.

Modifying and maintaining existing systems for adaptation to business and/or technology changes.

Engaging directly with IT management, development teams, technical delivery teams, and vendors to ensure successful design, development, and delivery of technology-based solutions.

Driving the software change.

Maheen Dizayn Etiket (BD.) Ltd.

2 years 11 months

UI/ UX Front End Developer

December 2018 - October 2021 (2 years 11 months)

Bangladesh

Design and develop front-end interface assigned by the reporting seniors.

Design and develop programming systems making specific determinations about system performance.

Ensure responsive websites/software pages development.

Communicates with project teams & Explains progress on the development effort.

Translates designs and style guides provided by the Graphics Design team into functional user interfaces, ensuring cross-browser compatibility and performance.

Ensure bug fixing while developing UI/UX front end pages/interfaces.

#### Programmer

June 2020 - September 2021 (1 year 4 months)

Narayanganj District, Dhaka, Bangladesh

Work on TypeScript, Node JS, SQL Server, Git

Chakri.com

Web Developer

October 2016 - November 2018 (2 years 2 months)

Gulshan Tower (7th Floor), Gulshan North C.A. Gulshan-2, Dhaka-1212

Work on both operating systems – Linux & Windows

Good knowledge in PHP Frameworks including Laravel, Zend Framework, OOP & MySQL.

Demonstrable knowledge of HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap etc.

Good knowledge in database design and queries.

Work on projects individually or as a part of the team.

Willing to learn new applications and work in highly challenging, creative projects.

Recruitment Management System (RMS) Development

Content Management System (CMS) Development

Work on sales team and content team requirements

Bug fixing

Email Template HTML Design for digital marketing

Technical support to clients

Develops and maintains technical relationships with System Administrator team.

Makes telephone calls and receive for technical support.

Keeps management informed by submitting activity and results reports, such as daily reports, weekly, and monthly.

Solve of user technical problems and complaints

Keeping the record in proper manner for all kinds of official correspondence.

Attending meeting, coordination with Clients and in-house.

Report Generate based on requirements

**Prothom Alo Jobs** 

Web Developer

May 2012 - September 2016 (4 years 5 months)

19, Karwan Bazar, Dhaka-1219

It was a sister concern of Prothom Alo.

Job Responsibility:

Develop Prothom-alojobs.com based on sales team and content team requirements

Bug fixing

Email Template HTML Design for digital marketing

Technical support to our clients(Employer)

Develops and maintains technical relationships with core IT team of Prothom Alo

Makes telephone calls and receive to existing Jobseekers for Jobseeker technical support.

Keeps management informed by submitting activity and results reports, such as daily reports, weekly, and monthly.

Solve of user technical problems and complaints

Keeping the record in a proper manner for all kinds of official correspondence.

Attending meeting, coordination with Clients and in-house.

Report Generate based on requirements

OG Software Itd.

Programmer

November 2011 - February 2012 (4 months)

Mirpur, Dhaka

## Education

Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology
Post Graduation Diploma (PGD), Institute of Information and Communication
Technology (IICT), BUET · (2012 - 2015)

### **IDB-BISEW**

Post Graduation Diploma, Web Development · (2009 - 2010)

National University (Eden Mohilla College) Master of Science, Mathematics · (2007 - 2008)

National University (Eden Mohilla College)
Bachelor of Science, Mathematics · (2002 - 2006)